<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hoang Ho</title>
    <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hoang Ho</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Zeran Wu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hoang-ho.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(Notes 3) CompSci 677 Distributed System - Editting</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_3/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 13: Transaction ACID properties
Atomicity: all operations succeed or none of them succeeds
Consistent
Isolation: Transaction executes as if it is the only transaction in the system. Ensures that the concurrent execution of transactions results in a system state that would be obtained if transactions were executed sequentially (serializability).
Durability: Changes are permanent once transaction completes (commits to disk)
Example:
ABORT_TRANSACTION will also abort the previous reservation because of atomicity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Notes 2) CompSci 677 Distributed System - Editting</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_2/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 8: Lecture 9: Naming Names are used to share resources, uniquely identify entities and refer to locations
Need to map from name to the entity it refers
Approaches to naming Two approaches to naming:
 Hierarchical (e.g. www.cnn.com) Hashed-based  Names spaces (File Names, URL) Name Space: Hierarchical directory structure (DAG)
 Each file name is a unique path in the DAG Resolution of /home/steen/mbox a traversal of the DAG  Resolving File Names across Machines NFS mount protocol: map a remote node onto local DAG</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Notes 1) CompSci 677 Distributed System - Editting</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_1/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This is my personal class notes for CompSci 677 taught by Prof. Marco Serafini at UMass Amherst Spring 2021. All images are taken from the free version of textbook and from slides. Notes contains extracts from textbook and from slides. This notes are for me to review the materials and for you if you are looking to review some concepts.
 Lecture 1: High level concepts 4 important goals for a DS:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A year in review - 2020</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/2021-01-20-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/2021-01-20-review/</guid>
      <description>5 months later, I still vividly remember my last day at Amazon. I knew very well from the week before what the outcome was and what would happen on that very last day. But I was just a navie kid (I still am), wishing on a shooting star. I cried as it happened &amp;hellip;
Ending 2019 with all goals accomplished, I started 2020 with a complacent attitude and gradually lost momentum for work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Hoang Random fun facts:
 I come from a port city in central Vietnam, famous for beautiful beach, awesome food and sunny weather I&amp;rsquo;m a first generation college graduate I changed my major three times in college (Actuarial Science -&amp;gt; Mathematics and Economics -&amp;gt; Mathematics) I have two middle names  I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on:
 this site possibly your next project check out my github for more  Interest I&amp;rsquo;m currently interested in Distributed System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/z/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/z/</guid>
      <description>:-)
Look at the stars
Look how they shine for you
And everything you do
Yeah&#39; they were all Yellow
I came along
I wrote a song for you
And all the things you do
it was called Yellow
So then I took my turn
Oh what a thing to have done
And it was all Yellow
Your skin
Oh yeah&#39; your skin and bones
Turn into something beautiful
Do you know?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
