<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tech, notes, Distributed System on Hoang Ho</title>
    <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/categories/tech-notes-distributed-system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tech, notes, Distributed System on Hoang Ho</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Zeran Wu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hoang-ho.github.io/categories/tech-notes-distributed-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(Notes 3) CompSci 677 Distributed System - Editting</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_3/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 13: Transaction ACID properties
Atomicity: all operations succeed or none of them succeeds
Consistent
Isolation: Transaction executes as if it is the only transaction in the system. Ensures that the concurrent execution of transactions results in a system state that would be obtained if transactions were executed sequentially (serializability).
Durability: Changes are permanent once transaction completes (commits to disk)
Example:
ABORT_TRANSACTION will also abort the previous reservation because of atomicity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Notes 2) CompSci 677 Distributed System - Editting</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_2/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 8: Lecture 9: Naming Names are used to share resources, uniquely identify entities and refer to locations
Need to map from name to the entity it refers
Approaches to naming Two approaches to naming:
 Hierarchical (e.g. www.cnn.com) Hashed-based  Names spaces (File Names, URL) Name Space: Hierarchical directory structure (DAG)
 Each file name is a unique path in the DAG Resolution of /home/steen/mbox a traversal of the DAG  Resolving File Names across Machines NFS mount protocol: map a remote node onto local DAG</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Notes 1) CompSci 677 Distributed System - Editting</title>
      <link>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hoang-ho.github.io/posts/distributedsystemnotes_1/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This is my personal class notes for CompSci 677 taught by Prof. Marco Serafini at UMass Amherst Spring 2021. All images are taken from the free version of textbook and from slides. Notes contains extracts from textbook and from slides. This notes are for me to review the materials and for you if you are looking to review some concepts.
 Lecture 1: High level concepts 4 important goals for a DS:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
